<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-28T01:32:33-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MPower Canada</title><subtitle>Building capacities for sustainable impact</subtitle><entry><title type="html">CAPACITY BUILDING</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/11/27/CAPACITY-BUILDING.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CAPACITY BUILDING" /><published>2019-11-27T16:09:10-07:00</published><updated>2019-11-27T16:09:10-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/11/27/CAPACITY-BUILDING</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/11/27/CAPACITY-BUILDING.html">&lt;h4&gt;FUND DEVELOPMENT&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supported by a successful track record of growing programs and business expansion, our expertise &amp;amp; knowledge in proposal development spans all levels of government funding, foundations as well as corporate social responsibility programs. From project development to all aspects of proposal writing, clear, concise writing and extensive knowledge of programs and services in the industry, we have delivered innovative program designs and developed winning proposals since 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/news/assets/img/about1-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;FUND DEVELOPMENT&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;PROJECT MANAGEMENT&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With extensive experience &amp;amp; a strong record of success in full-cycle project management, our project management services include the core stages of Project Preparation; Project Planning, Project Implementation and Project Evaluation. Our track record of over a decade of dedicated service to the charitable sector demonstrates a history of exceeding deliverables &amp;amp; expectations, leading to program innovation &amp;amp; organizational expansion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/news/assets/img/about1-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;PROJECT MANAGEMENT&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">FUND DEVELOPMENT</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Job Talk Canada</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/11/01/Job-Talk-Canada.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Job Talk Canada" /><published>2019-11-01T14:30:51-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T14:30:51-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/11/01/Job-Talk-Canada</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/11/01/Job-Talk-Canada.html">&lt;p&gt;The first JobTalk class was delivered in 2008 in Calgary, Alberta, Canada. This course was designed and delivered by Mae Chun, a Canadian professional with over 10 years of experience working with new immigrants to Canada and helping them find meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants are equipped with knowledge of the Canadian job market, understand the job application process and learn the right way to apply for jobs in Canada. In addition, students gain insights into Canadian culture, especially culture in the workplace. Over the years, JobTalk has been credited with helping many new immigrants from all over the world find work, from entry level to professional jobs. Such countries include China, Taiwan, Korea, Japan, India, Brazil, Columbia, Peru, Nigeria, Kenya, England, Scotland, Egypt, Iran and many more. Repeatedly so, many students expressed the need for such information to be available in their home countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We listened. JobTalkCanada is the result and its primary mission is to provide updated, reliable and relevant job search information to those wishing to immigrate to Canada. Our services to job seekers who are new to Canada are based on the collective experiences of many qualified, experienced and passionate individuals interested in the success of new Canadians. JobTalkCanada is an information hub and a skills training medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Follow us. Connect with us. Be an INFORMED job seeker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The first JobTalk class was delivered in 2008 in Calgary, Alberta, Canada. This course was designed and delivered by Mae Chun, a Canadian professional with over 10 years of experience working with new immigrants to Canada and helping them find meaningful work.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Good For All</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/11/01/Good-For-All.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good For All" /><published>2019-11-01T14:30:51-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T14:30:51-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/11/01/Good-For-All</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/11/01/Good-For-All.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We give back and uplift the lives of others by sharing blessings of love and thoughtfulness with those in need. Children in crisis. Seniors in isolation. Those in need of encouragement. We accept donations of excess inventories and send them on to say, “Someone’s thinking of you today”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We give back and uplift the lives of others by sharing blessings of love and thoughtfulness with those in need. Children in crisis. Seniors in isolation. Those in need of encouragement. We accept donations of excess inventories and send them on to say, “Someone’s thinking of you today”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Age discrimination</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/10/15/age-discrimination.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Age discrimination" /><published>2019-10-15T16:09:10-06:00</published><updated>2019-10-15T16:09:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/10/15/age-discrimination</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/10/15/age-discrimination.html">&lt;p&gt;Age discrimination in the workplace is real, pervasive and affects workers of all ages. But for those who are past 55, the implications can be profound and life-altering (and not in a good way). Many of us can relate to the struggles of finding meaningful work beyond a certain age and the process of doing that impacts our sense of self-worth, the notion of ‘usefulness’ to society, the feeling of significance and contribution. Consciously or unconsciously, our sense of ‘usefulness’ is tied to that paycheck. Bottom line is, we can’t control how others behave, think or treat us but what we CAN control is how we respond, how we value ourselves and how we CHOOSE to use the wealth of experience, skills and knowledge to the benefit of others. Ditch the victim mentality. Reach out and support one another.  &lt;strong&gt;#wellness #wecan #worth #self&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/12/business/millennials-age-discrimination.html&quot;&gt;An Open Letter (and a Rant) on Age Discrimination at Work &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Age discrimination in the workplace is real, pervasive and affects workers of all ages. But for those who are past 55, the implications can be profound and life-altering (and not in a good way). Many of us can relate to the struggles of finding meaningful work beyond a certain age and the process of doing that impacts our sense of self-worth, the notion of ‘usefulness’ to society, the feeling of significance and contribution. Consciously or unconsciously, our sense of ‘usefulness’ is tied to that paycheck. Bottom line is, we can’t control how others behave, think or treat us but what we CAN control is how we respond, how we value ourselves and how we CHOOSE to use the wealth of experience, skills and knowledge to the benefit of others. Ditch the victim mentality. Reach out and support one another. #wellness #wecan #worth #self</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The grannies keeping a school alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/10/01/the-grannies-keeping-a-school-alive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The grannies keeping a school alive" /><published>2019-10-01T16:09:10-06:00</published><updated>2019-10-01T16:09:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/10/01/the-grannies-keeping-a-school-alive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/10/01/the-grannies-keeping-a-school-alive.html">&lt;p&gt;These grannies may be keeping a school alive but I wonder if they realize that their actions are a powerful influencer for those of us who work everyday to effect impactful and sustainable social change. Such results can only be achieved through relentless innovation, being responsive to emerging needs, unwavering commitment to the greater good and tireless dedication to keep it going. To all of you out there doing such work, I SALUTE all of you. Too often, the work is unrecognized, under-appreciated and undervalued. But when we see impact such as in this article, the reward is deeply satisfying &amp;amp; simply priceless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://https://www.bbc.com/news/av/world-asia-50425019/south-korean-grannies-keeping-a-school-alive&quot;&gt;bbc.com &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">These grannies may be keeping a school alive but I wonder if they realize that their actions are a powerful influencer for those of us who work everyday to effect impactful and sustainable social change. Such results can only be achieved through relentless innovation, being responsive to emerging needs, unwavering commitment to the greater good and tireless dedication to keep it going. To all of you out there doing such work, I SALUTE all of you. Too often, the work is unrecognized, under-appreciated and undervalued. But when we see impact such as in this article, the reward is deeply satisfying &amp;amp; simply priceless.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We’re not crying, you are!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/09/17/were-not-crying-you-are.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We're not crying, you are!" /><published>2019-09-17T16:09:10-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-17T16:09:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/09/17/were-not-crying-you-are</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/09/17/were-not-crying-you-are.html">&lt;p&gt;This is such a delightful story - seniors sharing their wisdom with students, just in time for back to school.  Seniors need meaningful engagement and this is such a wonderful way of doing it. This went viral on social media. They must all be so proud. Well done! Josephine Pon** #seniors #students #wellness**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://https://www.narcity.com/news/ca/ab/alberta-senior-share-heartwarming-back-to-school-advice&quot;&gt;Seniors At This Alberta Care Home Have Just Shared This Amazing Advice For Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is such a delightful story - seniors sharing their wisdom with students, just in time for back to school. Seniors need meaningful engagement and this is such a wonderful way of doing it. This went viral on social media. They must all be so proud. Well done! Josephine Pon** #seniors #students #wellness**</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Essence of sustainable community development</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/09/10/essence-of-sustainable-community-development.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Essence of sustainable community development" /><published>2019-09-10T16:09:10-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-10T16:09:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/09/10/essence-of-sustainable-community-development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/09/10/essence-of-sustainable-community-development.html">&lt;p&gt;It does take a whole community of supports to effect transformative change. Our latest project involve tackling seniors social isolation in the North Calgary region. It took 6 months of painstaking efforts &amp;amp; a never-say-die spirit to get the results we saw today - a class full of immigrant seniors showing up to learn basic English conversation. I wish you could see the smiles, hear the laughter, feel the sense of accomplishment as one after another, reluctant English speakers speak their first complete sentence in English. High fives were flying all over the room!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results such as these took piecing together collaborations from all possible stakeholders - every community association in the area, the local library &amp;amp; recreation organization, the City of Calgary Government of Alberta, Josephine Pon  local ethno-cultural organizations &amp;amp; other grassroots groups, and hours of volunteer labour. This in a nutshell is the very essence of sustainable community development - an initiative that benefits the local community, made possible by the combined efforts of the local community and built-in sustainability achieved through the volunteer efforts of the local community. Together Everyone does Achieve More!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It does take a whole community of supports to effect transformative change. Our latest project involve tackling seniors social isolation in the North Calgary region. It took 6 months of painstaking efforts &amp;amp; a never-say-die spirit to get the results we saw today - a class full of immigrant seniors showing up to learn basic English conversation. I wish you could see the smiles, hear the laughter, feel the sense of accomplishment as one after another, reluctant English speakers speak their first complete sentence in English. High fives were flying all over the room!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">World Seniors Citizens Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/08/21/World-Seniors-Citizens-Day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="World Seniors Citizens Day" /><published>2019-08-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/08/21/World-Seniors-Citizens-Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/08/21/World-Seniors-Citizens-Day.html">&lt;p&gt;World Seniors Citizens Day was proclaimed by the UN General Assembly in 1990 and celebrated on Aug 21 each year. Let’s honor, respect and appreciate their lifelong contribution to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Delhi: World Senior Citizens Day is celebrated on August 21 every year across the world. It prov…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mynation.com/world/world-senior-citizen-day-2019-tribute-to-dedication-achievements-services-here-how-to-celebrate-pwkjqi&quot;&gt;Read more at&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">World Seniors Citizens Day was proclaimed by the UN General Assembly in 1990 and celebrated on Aug 21 each year. Let’s honor, respect and appreciate their lifelong contribution to the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Discrimination Is Hard to Prove</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/05/29/discrimination-is-hard-to-prove.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Discrimination Is Hard to Prove" /><published>2019-05-29T16:09:10-06:00</published><updated>2019-05-29T16:09:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/05/29/discrimination-is-hard-to-prove</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/05/29/discrimination-is-hard-to-prove.html">&lt;p&gt;This article resonates because many will relate to it. Discrimination IS hard to prove, and so is bullying, harassment, racism and all other insidious acts of violations that leaves no visible signs of injury. Worst yet, even when there are witnesses to the act, the onus still lies on the victim to prove that damage was done. Truth is, most people choose to look away, stay silent or worse, submit to the power of the perpetrator. Until and unless more people speak up and speak out against all violations of basic human rights, the suffering and injustice will remain. Every voice matters and it all begins with just one voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#speakup #bullying #harassment #racism #discrimination&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/22/health/age-discrimination-legal.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Discovery&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot;&gt;Discrimination Is Hard to Prove, Even Harder to Fix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This article resonates because many will relate to it. Discrimination IS hard to prove, and so is bullying, harassment, racism and all other insidious acts of violations that leaves no visible signs of injury. Worst yet, even when there are witnesses to the act, the onus still lies on the victim to prove that damage was done. Truth is, most people choose to look away, stay silent or worse, submit to the power of the perpetrator. Until and unless more people speak up and speak out against all violations of basic human rights, the suffering and injustice will remain. Every voice matters and it all begins with just one voice.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hong Kong, chief executive Carrie Lam addresses</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/05/28/hong-kong-chief-executive-carrie-lam-addresses.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hong Kong, chief executive Carrie Lam addresses" /><published>2019-05-28T16:09:10-06:00</published><updated>2019-05-28T16:09:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/05/28/hong-kong-chief-executive-carrie-lam-addresses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2019/05/28/hong-kong-chief-executive-carrie-lam-addresses.html">&lt;p&gt;It is intriguing to watch high profile &lt;strong&gt;#leaders&lt;/strong&gt; perform under conditions of extreme pressure and in the video below, Mdm. Carrie Lam delivers her apology to the Hong Kong people. Whatever your political stance is on this, people HAVE to be offended by this insult of a  question from the CBS reporter, “Critics have said that you are a habitual liar and that you have to cry today to be believed. How do you feel about that?” (full clip found at 30.55 min.) Habitual liar, I don’t care. But ‘cry’? Seriously? It is offensive, sexist and totally degrading. The sting of the insult comes from the realization that such a comment would never be delivered if a man was standing at that podium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#sexism #discrimination #racism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i/events/1140202329590751233&quot;&gt;Hong Kong’s chief executive Carrie Lam addresses the media amid massive protests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It is intriguing to watch high profile #leaders perform under conditions of extreme pressure and in the video below, Mdm. Carrie Lam delivers her apology to the Hong Kong people. Whatever your political stance is on this, people HAVE to be offended by this insult of a question from the CBS reporter, “Critics have said that you are a habitual liar and that you have to cry today to be believed. How do you feel about that?” (full clip found at 30.55 min.) Habitual liar, I don’t care. But ‘cry’? Seriously? It is offensive, sexist and totally degrading. The sting of the insult comes from the realization that such a comment would never be delivered if a man was standing at that podium.</summary></entry></feed>